SUNIL SUCKOO

Education

2016 Amherst College (3.74 GPA)

Anthropology

Magna Cum Laude Honors

2015 Danish Institute for Study Abroad

Gender Studies

Employment

WundermanSeattle, WAPlanning/Strategy InternOct 2016 to Present

- Introduce UX and other formal research methods to Planning/Strategy team.
- Plan ongoing mixed-method research projects on Microsoft and T-Mobile users.
- Collaborate with cross-functional teams (creatives, copywriters, etc.) to create multi-channel advertisements.

Amherst College Resident Counselor (RC) Office of Student Affairs Aug 2013 to May 2014, Aug 2015 to May 2016

- Planned 20+ events with nearly perfect attendance (20-25 students) using survey and ethnographic data.
- Co-founded the RC Council, which successfully advocated a +30% salary and +150% yearly budget.

Department of Anthropology and Sociology Jun 2015 to Aug 2015

Gregory S. Call Research Fellow

- Conducted preliminary thesis research (ethnography, field studies, survey design).
- Awarded \$4,280 summer living stipend and full funding (\$1,500+) for several concise (1-3 pages) and in-depth (10-15 pages) thesis research proposals and itemized budgets.

University of Chicago Mellon Initiative Research Fellow

Chicago, IL Jun 2014 to Aug 2014

- Conducted qualitative research (ethnography, field studies, interviews, card sorting) on diversity in higher education.
- Presented at Leadership Alliance National Symposium (350+ undergraduates, 50 grad students, 25 scholars) and UChicago Research Symposium (20+ scholars).
- Proposed 10 new paid diversity center staff positions to Amherst College.

Projects

The World of Millennials

Oct 2016 to Present

- Conduct interviews, desk research, and fieldwork on Wunderman employees.
- Present research to Planning/Strategy team to move beyond the "Digital Native."

Millennial Cyborgs (Senior Thesis)

Aug 2015 to May 2016

- Wrote 110-page thesis on American millennials' use of technology, based on 5+ years of ethnography, field studies, diary studies, interviews, and 140+ survey responses.
- Presented to 50+ students, 20+ doctoral scholars, and 10+ business professionals at the Five College Anthropology Conference.

Summary

- Marketing researcher, with a focus on American millennials.
- Record of implementing effective change.
- Interests: Random Acts of Kindness, Independent Films, Event Planning, and Flamin' Hot® Products.

Skills

Ethnography, Field Studies, Diary Studies, Interviewing, Survey Design, Card Sorting, Focus Groups, Presentation, Usability Testing, Affinity Diagram

Awards

Donald S. Pitkin Prize 2016 Amherst College Anthropology-Sociology Department

\$400 to best Anthropology-Sociology thesis out of 12 honors theses.

Watson Fellowship Finalist 2016

2012

2012

6% admission rate, 4 students selected on strength of research proposal, personal statement, and interview.

Valedictorian 20 Hazel Park High School Rank 1 out of 200+ students.

Wilfred D. Webb Award 2012 Hazel Park High School

The valedictorian with the strongest commitment to community service.

Mathematics Award HPHS Department of Mathematics

\$25 to most promising AP Calculus student out of 20 students.

Writing Award 2012 HPHS Department of English

\$25 to AP English student with the best writing skills out of 25 students.